上周的视频是关于重新访问上的剥削练习/Protostar的0级格式。
a modern ubuntu system.
我们玩弄它，看是否能找到利用它的方法，但是
the end I wasn’t able to solve it.
但对我来说幸运的是，一个名为wcbowling on reddit的用户认为它也很有趣，实际上
had a method to exploit it.
So let’s have a look at it.
这是wcbowlings post：
我喜欢回到像这样的老挑战中去：）设法得到了相当可靠的利用，
normally under 500 iterations.
对它的工作方式有一个更高层次的描述：
Overwrite the GOT entry for __stack_chk_fail with an address so we jump there instead.
地址可以通过argv传入，不能使用空值，但可以使用空字符串
instead.
由于argv的位置是半随机的，它需要大约500次迭代，这是非常合理的
64位
所以很明显我没有弄明白，这意味着我不知道什么
and here is a learning opportunity for me.
So I’m not going to pretend I knew this.
For whatever reason I never noticed that __stack_chk_fail is in the global offset table.
原因可能是，我从未遇到过有这些限制的挑战？
我们有a）一个格式字符串漏洞，通常允许我们在任何地方写任何东西b）
在格式字符串vuln之后没有libc函数，我们可以在全局偏移量中覆盖它
表和c）其中还存在缓冲区溢出
with a stack cookie.
So I really like this challenge now, because the solution is so clever.
因此，当堆栈cookie通过
buffer overflow is also on the global offset table.
这意味着我们的目标是通过覆盖got将代码执行重定向到获胜消息。
entry for __stack_chk_fail.
And then do a buffer overflow, to trigger that function.
要写入全局偏移表条目，我们必须将地址放在
the stack, so that we can use %n with the format string vulnerability.
And the issue is that it contains nullbytes which we can’t pass in via the arguments.
我认为这些参数是字符串复制到堆栈上的？
So we can’t enter arbitrary nullbytes.
But wcbowling had a cool trick with empty strings as arguments.
Because a string ends with a nullbyte, so an empty string is just null.
我想我有一个超早期的视频来讨论环境和争论
堆栈，但快速回顾一下，您有argv[]char指针数组，所以它是一个带有
addresses that point to the strings.
And then you just have memory with all the strings.
And so this way you can get the address with null-bytes on to the stack.
Pretty clever, I never thought about this before.
And now you basically just have to put everything together.
wcbowling使用pwnlib来实现这个漏洞，它是一个非常有用的python库，检查
it out.
所以这里的magic格式字符串是用一个大的偏移量构建在堆栈中的，希望
hits the addresses passed in via the arguments.
And so there are two single byte writes.
为什么只写两个字节？
好吧，got已经包含了一个几乎是目标地址的地址，除了最后一个
two bytes.
So you can just reuse most of it.
Then this is being executed in a loop until the winning message is shown.
The stack has some randomized offsets, thus you have to try it a few times.
Here is the asciicinema recording by wcbowling.
顺便说一下，如果你对挑战有问题，你给我写封电子邮件，你可以用它
to record a screencast so I can actually see how you debug it and what the problem is.
So while I understand now the basic idea, I still wanted to implement it myself.
您必须解决一些挑战，例如，什么是良好的堆栈偏移
to hit the arguments, and the alignment of the address through the arguments.
And while I was doing that and struggling with exactly those details, I had an epiphany.
我很快就感激WCbowling分享了这一成果，因为它促使我发现
this.
所以我发现了一个100%可靠的利用这个挑战，你不能相信
how excited that makes me.
尽管我不得不承认，它可能只对我编译的二进制文件有效，对某些人也有效。
else it might not work, you will see in a second why.
So here it is.
That’s all.
And when we execute it, you can see it gets into an execution loop of the winning message.
虽然它看起来像一个简单的格式字符串漏洞，但填充会增加
打印字符数、地址和写入地址的%n或%hn
are quite a few beautiful puzzle pieces here.
所以，当我在玩重写got条目
__stack_check_fail.
wcbowling had two writes and placed the address in the arguments, which made it so unreliable.
我想，如果我们把地址放在字符串中，就像我在字符串中那样，也许我们会幸运的。
the last video.
But there is one problem.
打印的字符串来自参数，参数具有不可预测的
position.
但是字符串是用sprintf格式化为缓冲区的，缓冲区将具有固定的相对值
position on our stack.
所以基本上格式字符串将被计算，所以首先它用1640字符处理%d
padding and places it into the buffer.
Then comes the raw bytes of the address, and places it.
And then comes the format modifier to write to an address on the stack.
所以现在这个地址的位置，刚刚写入缓冲区，是在一个固定的
偏移位置，我们总是用
214.
Though the problem is, we can’t have an arbitrary amount of bytes padding.
Because the address has to be 8byte alligned.
So we can only increase or decrease the padding in 8 byte steps.
Which affects the amounts of bytes we can write.
With %n.
It’s always in these 8 steps.
所以我们没有写任何东西的条件，但是我们可以写一些接近wilining的东西。
address.
Now there are two challenges.
首先，堆栈相当小，格式化结果被写入
堆栈，所以如果我们使用太多的填充来用%n写一个大的数字，那么堆栈就用完了
memory and get a segfault.
但wcbowling的技巧让我意识到，事实上我们可以增加
stack by just using more arguments.
It will add entries to the argv array and increase it.
第二个问题是，地址只写3个字节，所以如果
on the stack had other values in it, it won’t work.
我们需要把地址写在一个零的堆栈上，或者通常是一个小的堆栈上。
number before.
这也是论点再次帮助我们的地方，因为我们可以整理堆栈，
通过在argv数组中添加或删除条目，使堆栈足够大，并且我们
have a zero at the correct spot.
&lt；grunt&gt；我喜欢它！
所以现在我们知道了如何整理堆栈以写入got条目，但是我们仍然有这个问题
that we are not sure what to write because of our multiples of 8 restrictions.
我编写了一个简单的python函数，它用不同的
paddings and adjusts the amount of arguments and the write offset accordingly.
And I started by looking around the printing of the winning message.
所以理想情况下我们想写0x670，那是1648，但是由于我们的对齐限制
that doesn’t work.
Anyway, I was then just trying them, to see if anything interesting would come from it.
And luckily this one worked.
让我用gdb调试它，在sprintf之后，在检查堆栈之前设置一个断点。
cookie.
Let’s look at the stack.
这是用空格填充的%d个字符，用来打印我们想要的字符数。
write to.
And then here at the end is the target address we want to write to.
The GOT address.
We can also look now what value has been written there.
So we will jump to 0x40066b.
Let’s look at the disassembly and see where that would be.
66b.
嗯…等等！
地址无效，对吗？
It’s in between the compare and the jump-not-equal.
Let’s use x to print 3 instructions, instead of the disassemble command.
Do you see that.
WTF现在有移动，而不是CMP？
搞什么鬼？
Welcome to intel assembler and more advanced ROP.
这种性质被称为英特尔汇编程序的几何，在著名的ROP论文中，
but never heard anybody using that term.
总之，我们在预期指令的字节之间跳转，CPU是哑的，
it will just read those bytes and interpret them as assembler.
And so in this case, the cmp and jne turned into two simple moves.
这就是说，现在没有空头支票了，我们就跑到印刷品上印上了胜利的字样。
message.
当我们现在单步前进时，我们进入程序链接表进行堆栈检查失败，
我们跳到got条目，这是我们在vuln中的奇怪地址，我们执行mov，并且
then we call puts to print the message.